thinkquest.org 2007-12-11

# ThinkQuest Privacy Policy

OVERVIEW 

This Privacy Policy **(Policy)** applies to your use of the website accessible via the URL www.thinkquest.org **(Site)** , including ThinkQuest’s online website library (Library), as well as to online registration and participation in a ThinkQuest Competition (if applicable). Your use of the Site is subject to and contingent upon your agreement with the terms of this Policy. 

OTHER TERMS 

Your use of our Site is subject to and contingent upon your agreement with the ThinkQuest Website Terms of Use, which are hereby incorporated by reference. Participation in a ThinkQuest Competition **(Competition)** is governed by the applicable Evaluation Criteria and Rules as well as any other agreements required to be executed in order to participate in the Competition. The **Foundation** , we, or us refers to the Oracle Education Foundation, a California not-for-profit corporation. 

CHILDREN AND MINORS 

We encourage all young visitors to consult with their parents about how to best enjoy this Site and Library. The Foundation is aware that the nature of this Site means that a significant number of our users are young people. 

  * Submission of Personal Information through the Site: The websites housed in the Library do not contain functionality for the submission of Personal Information (as defined below), nor does the Foundation wish to receive Personal Information from minors (children under 13 years of age, or any other age defined under applicable law) through use of the Library. If the Foundation becomes aware that it has received unsolicited information from a minor through the Library, we will notify the minor that we may not accept his or her Personal Information and we will then expunge any related Personal Information from our records.
  * Submission of Personal Information through participation in the Competition: The Foundation does collect Personal Information from team coaches (Coaches) through the online registration process for the Competition (as described below) and collects Personal Information from minors’ parents or legal guardians in the event that a minor is a winner in a Competition in order to confirm that minor’s eligibility to participate in ThinkQuest Live. If the Foundation becomes aware that it has received unsolicited information from a minor, we will notify the minor that we may not accept his or her Personal Information and we will then expunge any related Personal Information from our records. 

CONTACTING THE FOUNDATION 

The Foundation respects user privacy and supports initiatives to preserve individual privacy on the Internet. We welcome any comments or questions users may have, and you should feel free to contact us by sending an email to [thinkquest.ww@oracle.com](mailto:thinkquest.ww@oracle.com), or by sending a letter to: 

Oracle Education Foundation  
Elizabeth Chase, Global Operations  
500 Oracle Parkway, MS 5OP890  
Redwood Shores, CA 94065  
650-607-2920 

INFORMATION WE COLLECT 

Personal Information 

Unless you provide it to us voluntarily, the Foundation does not collect Personal Information about you in connection with your use of this Site. In the case of Coaches, the Foundation may ask the Coach to provide Personal Information about other members of the team during the registration process, including the first name and age of team members. 

Notwithstanding above, Personal Information may be submitted to us for purposes of: (a) registering to receive additional information from us; (b) enrolling in the Competition, (c) registering online for the ThinkQuest Live event ( **ThinkQuest Live** ) and, if named a winner, managing your participation in the same; (d) your general use of the Site, such as your written or emailed request for information; and (e) in the case of Coaches, registering to use a non-public area of the Site (a “ **Site Forum** ”). The practices described in this Policy also apply to any Personal Information you provide to us in writing or by telephone. 

Personal Information that is submitted to the Foundation may include, depending on the relevant circumstances as described above: 

  * First and Last name
  * Email Address
  * School Name and School Address
  * Mailing Address
  * Telephone number
  * Age
  * Gender
  * Country of Citizenship
  * Demographic Information
  * Personal interests such as hobbies and sports, and other identifying information such as photographs.
  * Coaches will have the option of selecting an income level range for each member of the team when registering online for the Competition. This information will be reported only to the Foundation’s board of directors for purposes of confirming the Foundation’s participation in projects with low-income communities. 

As Coaches may be required to provide information about team members, Personal Information also includes information we ask you to provide about other people. Any information you provide to the Foundation must be true, accurate, current, non-misleading, and consistent and relevant for the purpose for which you are providing the information. You must have the authority to provide the information submitted to and through the Site, and you understand and agree that we may from time to time use the information submitted to verify such authority. 

THE FOUNDATION DOES NOT WISH TO RECEIVE ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION PERTAINING TO ANY INDIVIDUAL UNLESS ALL REQUISITE PERMISSIONS HAVE BEEN OBTAINED IN ADVANCE. YOU HEREBY REPRESENT AND WARRANT TO THE FOUNDATION THAT YOU HAVE FULL AUTHORITY TO SUBMIT THE PERSONAL AND OTHER INFORMATION REQUIRED FOR PARTICIPATION IN THE COMPETITION AND OTHER INTERACTIONS WITH US. 

Usage Data 

The Site automatically tracks certain information about your behavior during your visit. The information gathered includes the URL from which you accessed this Site, as well as certain information about your web browser and IP address **(Usage Data)**. This information enables us to determine where users are coming from and which parts of our Site they are using. We collect and store this aggregate Usage Data in order to measure the Site's performance and improve the Site's design and functionality. We may also share this aggregate Usage Data with third parties to illustrate how the Site is used and for other marketing or benchmarking purposes. In no event does any Usage Data contain any personally identifying information about our users. 

Cookies 

For the convenience of our visitors, we may store bits of information inside your computer. These bits of information are known as "cookies". Cookies are small pieces of data that a website sends to a web browser. websites often use cookies because they help keep track of things like an individual's preferences and personal interests in order to help site operators to evaluate how a site is being used. We may also use cookies to authenticate users. Authenticating users helps maintain the security of our Site. 

USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION 

We use the information you submit as follows: 

  * **Registration:** Registration is the process by which a Coach registers a team for participation in the Competition. We will use this information to process your registration, communicate with you regarding your team's participation in the Competition, and otherwise in accordance with the applicable Evaluation Criteria and Rules, which are hereby incorporated by reference. Once you have registered, you become a Registered User for purposes of this Policy.
  * **Site Forums:** Your Personal Information will also be used by the Foundation to verify your identity if you choose to register for a Site Forum. Coaches may gain access to a Site Forum by creating a combination of a unique user name and password that they select. The Foundation may use your Personal Information to verify your eligibility for each Site Forum. The Site Forums are hosted by an independent third party vendor, which has its own separate website terms and privacy policies. You should read these website terms and privacy policy before participating in any Site Forum. The Foundation does not make any representations regarding the terms and policies applicable to use of the Site Forums hosted by the independent third-party vendor. 
  * **Competition Submission:** Submitting a Competition entry may involve the submission of additional contact information or other Personal Information included in the actual entry ( **Submission Information** ). This Submission Information is used for the purpose of processing a team’s submission and may be shared with judges or Competition Partners (defined below) only in relation to the conduct, management and/or operation of the Competition. 
  * **ThinkQuest Live Registration:** As discussed above, the Foundation will collect additional Personal Information regarding Coaches, students and chaperones from teams that win a Competition. This information is required by law to claim the prize and/or required to be submitted for participation in ThinkQuest Live. This information makes it possible to confirm travel arrangements, travel visas and awards.
  * **Correspondence and Miscellaneous Queries:** Any Personal Information submitted as part of an inquiry will be used to respond to your question and undertake any further action as may be required by your request. For purposes of this Policy, non-Registered Users are referred to as **Public Visitors**. We do not retain the personally identifiable information submitted by Public Visitors beyond the period of time required to respond to the query or take other related actions, and all such information is regularly purged from our systems from time to time. 

DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION 

Other than as described in this section, the Foundation, its parent corporation, subsidiaries and Partners (as defined below) do not share your Personal Information with undisclosed third parties and the information is never used for marketing or other non-educational related functions. Other than as described below, the Foundation, its parent corporation, subsidiaries and Partners do not sell or rent Personal Information collected via this Site to third parties nor will your Personal Information or the Personal Information of others be used for any commercial purposes. 

Subject to applicable law, we may disclose your Personal Information: 

  * To employees of Oracle U.S.A. and/or its subsidiaries for the purpose of operating and maintaining the Library and conducting, managing and operating the Competition; 
  * To unaffiliated educational organizations, such as departments of education, ministries of education and universities which collaborate with the Foundation as part of a Competition pursuant to written contracts (Partners) and which are required to uphold and maintain the Foundation's policies with respect to privacy and the treatment of your Personal Information;
  * To other persons as permitted or required by applicable law or regulation for purposes of (1) conducting, managing and operating the Competition and the Library, and (2) arranging and confirming participation in and travel to ThinkQuest Live. ; and
  * To law enforcement personnel and agencies, or as part of a legal process, in order to protect our property or in furtherance of an investigation regarding a breach of the Site rules and policies, unauthorized access to or use of the Site or any other prohibited activities. 

Any access to such information will be limited to the purpose for which such information was provided or is otherwise required. 

In the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, dissolution, or transfer of substantially all of the assets of the Foundation, Personal Information and/or Usage Data submitted by you via this Site may be sold, assigned, or transferred to the party acquiring all or substantially all of the equity and/or assets of the Foundation in order to permit the party to continue the operation of the Site. Subject to your ability to opt-out as described below, by using this Site and submitting your information to us, you consent to the sale and transfer of your information as described in this paragraph.  

CONSENT TO PROCESSING 

Our Partners are located throughout the world. Accordingly, information may be sent worldwide to countries that have a different level of privacy protection than the United States. By using our Site, or providing information to the Foundation, you understand and unambiguously consent to the collection, processing, transfer and use of information in the United States and other countries and territories, for the purposes set forth in this Policy. You hereby consent to the collection, processing and disclosure by the Foundation of your Personal Information as described under this Policy, including but not limited to the transfer of your Personal Information between the Foundation and its Partners in accordance with this Policy. For further certainty, any consent relating to a right to transfer information referred to in this paragraph shall be deemed to include your consent to the transfer of the applicable Personal Information to a jurisdiction which may have a different level of privacy protection than that available in your own country. 

OPT-OUT CHOICES 

Registered Users may "opt-out" of (1) receiving communications from the Foundation (except for communications necessary for your use of the Site or your participation in a Competition), or (2) any other consent previously granted for a specific purpose concerning your personally identifiable information (including your consent to our sharing your information with our Partners), by logging in to the applicable Manage Teams page and selecting “Delete Account”. Please be aware that requests for the deletion of information from our databases may result in your disqualification from or inability to participate in the Competition. 

REVIEWING OR CHANGING INFORMATION 

If you are a Registered User, you may ask to review, change or delete information previously provided to us by logging in to the Manage Teams page. Please be aware that requests for the deletion of information from our databases may result in your disqualification from or inability to participate in the Competition. 

OTHER WEBSITES 

This Policy applies only to www.thinkquest.org. The Foundation, its affiliates and subsidiaries operate many websites for different purposes and in multiple jurisdictions where local laws may apply. This Site includes links to certain affiliated sites, including the Site Forums, and to other educational resource and non-profit websites, including access to content, products and services of such affiliated and non-affiliated sites ( **Other Sites** ). When you click on a link to these Other Sites, you will leave this Site. Prior to accessing Other Sites or non-Foundation content via this Site, we urge you to familiarize yourself with the individual privacy and other terms for each linked or framed site prior to submitting any personally identifiable information. 

SECURITY 

The Foundation takes seriously the security of the information it collects. The Foundation has therefore implemented technology and security policies and procedures intended to reduce the risk of accidental destruction or loss, or the unauthorized disclosure or access to, such information, reasonably appropriate to the nature of the data concerned. 

UPDATES TO PRIVACY POLICY 

The Foundation may, in its sole discretion, update this Policy at any time and from time to time, by posting the amended Policy on this Site. The amended Policy shall be effective upon posting and flagged to indicate it has been updated. Your access to or use of the Site following an update shall be deemed consent to the revised Policy. If you are a Registered User, amendments to this Policy may be sent to you via email or such other form of communication as you have requested. We urge each visitor to refer back to this page regularly and especially prior to providing or updating any Personal Information. 

LAST UPDATED: **August 15, 2005**
